Guide to the John M. Orr papers, 1790-1911
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
John M. Orr papers 1790-1911
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Orr, John M.
8.4 Linear Feet Approx. 9,605 Items
John M. Orr was a lawyer residing in Leesburg, Virginia.
The John M. Orr papers include legal and business correspondence and papers, and other items relating to Orr's activities as meat supply agent for the Confederate Army, his legal work for railroads, and his interest in the Southern racial problem and in colonization as a possible solution. Includes records of Orr as a commission merchant, mercantile and legal office accounts of Orr and Arthur Lee Rogers, and court records of Loudoun and Fauquier counties, Virginia, including an execution record book for Loudon County, Virginia. Other manuscript volumes include notes for suits, ledgers, and a journal.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John M. Orr papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 1933 to 1951.
Collection Overview
The John M. Orr papers include legal and business correspondence and papers, and other items relating to Orr's activities as meat supply agent for the Confederate Army, his legal work for railroads, and his interest in the Southern racial problem and in colonization as a possible solution. Includes records of Orr as a commission merchant, mercantile and legal office accounts of Orr and Arthur Lee Rogers, and court records of Loudoun and Fauquier counties, Virginia, including an execution record book for Loudon County, Virginia. Other manuscript volumes include notes for suits, ledgers, and a journal.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Orr, John M.
Rogers, Arthur Lee
Confederate States of America. Army -- Supplies and stores
African Americans -- Colonization
Commission merchants -- Virginia -- Leesburg
Court records -- Virginia -- Fauquier County
Court records -- Virginia -- Loudoun County
Lawyers -- Virginia -- Leesburg
Meat industry and trade -- Confederate States of America
Railroads -- Southern States
Fauquier County (Va.) -- History -- Sources
Loudoun County (Va.) -- History -- Sources
Southern States -- Race relations
Description of Collection
- John M. Orr papers, 1790-1911 and undated, (21 boxes)
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1799-1858 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1859-1868 July 10 (Box 2)
    Includes provision reports and commissary receipts, 1861 Sep. 7-1861 Nov. 2.
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1868 July 13 - 1871 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1872-1875 May (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1875 June-1881 June (Box 5)
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1881 July-1886 (Box 6)
    Includes correspondence from The Supreme Court of Appeals.
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1887-1894 (Box 7)
    Includes correspondence from The Supreme Court of Appeals. Includes some printed papers
  - Correspondence and other papers, 1895-1905, and undated (Box 8)
    Includes some printed papers.
  - Legal papers, 1774-1858 (Box 9)
  - Legal papers, 1860-1872 (Box 10)
  - Legal papers, 1872-1893 (Box 11)
    Includes many State of Virginia, Loudon County "to wit" slips.
  - Legal papers, 1894-1908, and undated (Box 12)
  - Legal papers, undated (Box 13)
  - Bills/receipts, 1800-1859 (Box 14)
  - Bills/receipts, circa 1850-1859 (Box 15)
  - Bills/receipts, 1860-1869 (Box 16)
  - Bills/receipts and miscellaneous papers, 1870-1902 and undated (Box 17)
  - Bills/receipts, undated (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1881-1902 and undated
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, circa 1856-1896
  - Miscellaneous printed material, circa 1840-1902 (Box 20)
    These papers are not in chronological order.
  - Diaries (Box 20)
    Notebooks, primarily pocket-sized.
- John M. Orr Manuscript Volumes, 1846-1871, (14 volumes)
  - Collection account, 1848-1857 (Volume F:3228)
  - Collection book, 1854-1861 (Volume F:3229)
  - Copies of bonds, etc. 1847-1854, (3 vols.) (Volume M:3230-M3230.2)
  - Court record, Fauquier County, Virginia, 1847-1856 (Volume M:3231)
  - Day book, John Orr and Arthur Lee Rogers, Leesburg, Va., 1854-1855 (Volume L:3232)
  - Day book, John Orr, 1861-1875 (Volume F:3233)
  - Execution book, Loudon County Superior Court, Virginia, 1847-1853 (Volume M:3234)
  - Journal, 1868-1870 (Volume F:3235)
  - Ledger, 1846-1860 (Volume F:3236)
  - Ledger, 1846-1870 (Volume F:3237)
  - Memoranda for suits, etc., Orr and Rogers, 1854-1860 (Volume L:3238)
  - Memorandum book for suits, 1861-1871 (Volume L:3239)